American Philosophical Society. Phillips Fund for Native American Research Collection 1960-present Mss.497.3.Am4
American Philosophical Society
- American Philosophical Society. Phillips Fund for Native American Research Collection (Box 1-30)
  - Melnar, Lynette
    - "Caddo syntax and verb stem morphology, August 28, 1993 - September 25, 1993", 1994; Melnar, Lynette
  - "An Investigation of Ethnographic and Archaelogical Specimens Of Mescal beans...", 1976; Merrill, William Lewis
  - "Plains Miwok Language", 1993; Miller, Amy
    Report and field notes of work with Mabel Walloupe, last speaker (95p.)
    (F&S 4950)
  - "A survey of the Beaver Dialects with respect to tone marking", 2002-2003; Miller, Julia Colleen
    Includes report on research (2p.) and two sets of word lists, the first with elicited nominal forms (68 sentences, 25p.), the second elicited verbal forms (64 sentences, 24p.)
    Includes Julia Colleen Miller, "An acoustic analysis of tone in Doig River and Blueberry River Beaver" (MA Thesis, Univ. of Washington, 2003).
    Five CD ROMs:
    Elicitiation for tone, 2002 July 10 (informant: William Attachie)
    Elicitiation for tone, 2002 July 16 (informant: Annie Acko)
    Elicitiation for tone, 2002 July 19 (informant: Madeline Oker)
    Elicitiation for tone, 2002 July 20 (informant: May Apsassin)
    Elicitiation for tone, 2002 July 20 (informant: Lana Wolf)
  - "The Seminole Context of Wild Cat's Leadership, 1838-1850", 1995; Miller, Susan A.
    2 reports (1p. each); Wild Cat's Bones: Seminole Leadership in a Seminole Cosmos (Diss.: University of Nebraska, 1997): transferred to Printed Materials
  - "A analysis of 16th Century Spanish Tribute Documents in Juzgado Archives, Teposcolula, Mexico", 1977; Mitchell, Mary-Elizabeth B.
  - "The Stockbridge-Munsee community", 1965; Mochon, Marion
    Images include black and white photographs of the Stockbridge-Munsee reservation, Bowler, Wisconsin, of dwellings, 1965.
    (Freeman guide 4539)
  - "Field notes; 1984" [Warm Springs Reservation, Oregon/ linguistic data/ Wasco-Wishram lang.], 1985; Moore, Robert E.
  - Kutenai linguistic fieldwork, B.C., 1974, 1987; Morgan, Lawrence R.
    Report (2p.); transcripts of texts elicited from monolingual speaker, Roselie McCoy
    (F&S 4520b)
  - "Schools as Contested Space: an Ethnohistorical Study of Schooling on Fort Belknap Reservation", 1996; Morgan, Mindy
  - Mississippi Band of Choctaw, 1996; Mould, Thomas
    Report (1p.) and transcripts of interviews (49p.) with Terry Ben, Charles and Carmen Denson, Caroline Morris, Harley Vaughn, Estelline Tubby, Gladys Willis to "construct a cultural history of the community through local narratives" (regarding mounds, the annual fair, stickball, family dinners, etc.); seven 7" reel-to-reel tapes (Rec. 243)
  - "Political Middlemanship and the Double Bind: James D. Savage And The Fresno River Reservation" Diss., 1980; Munoz, Neva Jeanne Harkins
  - "Letter to Whitfield J. Bell, Jr.; June 19, 1972", Munro, Pamela
  - Nakayama, Toshihide
    - "Collection of Linguistics", 1993; Nakayama, Toshihide
    - "Collection of Nootka...", 1994; Nakayama, Toshihide
  - "Field work among the Florida Seminole Indians", 1978; Nathan, Michele
    (F&S 4548a)
  - Nevin, Bruce E.
    - "Work On The Yana Language...", 1970; Nevin, Bruce E.
      (F&S 4917)
    - "Transformation analysis of some "Transformation analysis analysis of some 'Grammatical morphemes' in Yana", 1971; Nevin, Bruce E.
      (F&S 4916)
  - "Lingustic Fieldwork on Passamaquoddy (Algonquian)", 1998; Ng, Eve
    (F&S 4699)
  - "Indian Relations and American Political Culture, 1784-1800", 1998; Nichols, David A.
  - Nichols, Lynne, Nichols, Lynn
    - [Linguistic fieldwork/ Zuni Pueblo], 1994; Nichols, Lynn
    - "Topics in Zuni Syntax", 1992; Nichols, Lynn
      Fieldwork at Zuni Pueblo, NM, including field notes, 1992, 1993, 1996 (166p.), papers: "DP and polysynthesis," Proc. Of the Northeast Linguistic Society (1997); "Agreement and lexical structure," Soc. for Generative Linguistics in the Old World Newsletter (1998); "Movement to specifiers," In D. Adger et al., eds. Specifiers: Minimalist Approaches (Oxford, 1999); "On the nature of switch reference," in Proc. of the West Coast Conference on Formal Linguistics (1999); "Topics in Zuni Syntax" (Diss.: Harvard, 1997)
  - Norcross, Amoena B.
    - [Transcriptions/ Shawnee noun incorporation], 1993; Norcross, Amoena B.
    - "Verbal Affixes and Verbal Categories", 1995; Norcross, Amoena B.
  - "Vocabulary list of zoological & botanical specimens in Haida", 1979; Norton, Helen H.
  - "Report on syncretic and pre-Hispanic components of Tlaxcalan ritual kinship and folk Catholocism; Oct. 1, 1970", Nutini, Hugo G.
  - "Choctaws in the Revolutionary Age: A study of Power and Authority, 1750-1801", 1997; O'Brien, Greg
    Reports (2p.)
    (F&S 4521)
  - "Dominion and Civility: English Imperialism, Native America, and the Challenge of the First American Frontiers, 1585-1680", 1994; Oberg, Michael L.
  - Papers at Connecticut Historical Society #5, Occom, Samson, 1723-1792
  - "Semantics and discourse pragmatics of active case-making in Northern Pomo; 1986", O'Connor, Mary Catherine
  - Field work on the Bodega Miwok Language, 1977, 1978; Okrand, Marc
    Report, (2p.)
    (F&S 4137a)
  - "Cheyenne Texts. Collected in Norman Okla", 1964; Olson, Donald
  - "Inventory of pharyngeal resonant roots/ Spokane, Interior Salish", 1993; Orser, Brenda I. L.
  - "The Indian Fashion Show", 1995; Parezo, Nancy J.
    (F&S 4173)
  - "Field work on Pawnee", 1967, 1981; Parks, Douglas R.
    Report (1p., 1966); "Copying Pawnee Archival Material" (1p., 1981)
    (F&S 4647)
  - "Oral interviews with Iroquois individuals", 1997; Parmenter, Jon
    Report (1p.); photocopies of letters sent and received, etc.; four 7" reel-to-reel tapes (Rec. 251) of interviews with Chief Jacob Thomas; transcripts of interviews with Thomas, Gerald Alfred, Phil Monture, and Sheila Staats.
  - "The Navajo Particle Of Constituent Negation; 1973", 1974; Perkins, Ellavina
  - "The Brainerd Journal: Journal for the Mission to the Cherokees, 1817-1823", 1997; Phillips, Joyce B.; Phillips, P. Gary
    (F&S 4571)
  - "Report on his pilot linguistic study of the Ute Language...", 1966; Pia, J. Joseph
    (F&S 4765)
  - Some Syntactic Rules in Mohawk, 1962; Postal, Paul M.
    Diss.
    (F&S 4538)
  - Potter, Brian
    - "The Verb in San Carlos Apache", 1995; Potter, Brian
      Research summary; transcripts and revised transcript of interviews (76p.); four 7" reel-to-reel tapes (Rec. 248); Western Apache language database
    - "Comparative Studies in Athabaskan Syntax", 1997; Potter, Brian
      Comparative study of Western Apache and Sarcee, including report (1p.); two 7" reel-to-reel tapes (Rec. 249); 3.5" diskette of transcriptions, printed transcript, and dissertation, Wh/Indefinities and the Structure of the Clause in Western Apache (Diss.: UCLA, 1997): transferred to Printed Materials.
  - "Federal Policy Toward Native Americans: The Standing Rock Lakota", 1995; Potts, Steve
  - Powers, William K.
    Images include color slides of the Oglala reservation of Pine Ridge, South Dakota, with individual and group portraits, dwellings, buffalo skull, war bonnet, pipe, sweat lodge, dance shade, 1967-1968.
    - "Contemporary Oglala Music and Dance", 1967; Powers, William K.
    - "Indians of the Northern Plain", 1968; Powers, William K.
      (F&S 4683)
  - [Political history of the Pine Ridge Reservation (1879-1934)], 1995; Price, Catherine
  - "Micmac legends and folklore...", 1975; Proulx, Paul
  - "Recordings in the Carrier language", 1988; Prunet, Jean-Francois
  - "Report on linguistic fieldwork among the Cherokee; July 1972", Pulte, William
  - The K'iil'it and Di'haii Gwich'in of Northwestern Alaska, 1997; Raboff, Adeline Peter
    Report (1p.); paper: "Preliminary Study of the Western Gwich'in Bands," American Indian Culture and Research Journal 23:2 (1999), 1-25
    (F&S 4207)
  - "Study on Negro-Indians", 1971; Rachlin, Carol K.
  - Ramsay, Violeta
    - "The Morpho-syntax of language and the passive", 1987; Ramsay, Violeta
    - "Northern Paiute Stories. 1987", Ramsay, Violeta
  - Research concerning the Yamassee War, 1995; Ramsey, William L.
    Report (34p.)
    (F&S 4613)
  - "Notes on Walapai Verb Root Structure", 1977; Redden, James E.
  - "An ethnohistorical study of Lowland Quichua and Andean Cultural Exchange", 1987-1991; 2 TLsS (2p.); TMsS (1p.), 12 photocopies, 2 35mm slides; Reeve, Mary-Elizabeth
    From research conducted in 1987-1988. Includes photocopies of 17th and 18th century documents at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, and Sterling Library Map Collection, Yale.
  - "Political Organization Among the Kanien'kehaka (Mohawk) of Southern Quebec, 1890s to 1920s", 1997; Reid, Gerald F.
    Includes "Nativism, Nationalism, and Factionalism Among the Kanien 'Kehaka of Kahnawake During the Late 19th and Early 20th Centuries" a report (1p.); 7 cassette tapes (Rec. 261)
    (F&S 4867)
  - Rigsby, Bruce J., Rigsby, Bruce Joseph, 1937-
    - "Short Practical Dictionary of the Yakima Sahaptin Language. Contains Also: Coyote Doctors A Maiden (in Sahaptin)", 1971; Rigsby, Bruce Joseph, 1937-
    - "Report on 1966 Sahaptin Linguistic Field Research", Rigsby, Bruce Joseph, 1937-
      (F&S 4700)
  - Roark-Calnek, Sue N.
    - "Delaware Songs & Texts", 1977; Roark-Calnek, Sue N.
      (F&S 4222)
    - "Indian Way In Oklahoma", 1977; Roark-Calnek, Sue N.
      (F&S 4221a)
  - "An Archaeological and Ethnohistorical Investigation of Restricted Mobility Among Navajo Families in the Wupatki Basin, Arizona" Diss., 1993; Roberts, Alexandra
  - "Franz Boas: Ethnographer of the Northwest Coast", 1966; Rohner, Ronald P.
    (F&S 4602)
  - Rood, David S.
    - "Structure of the Wichita language", 1966; Rood, David S.
    - "Wichita language materials", 1970; Rood, David S.
      (F&S 4900)
  - "Constraints In Zapotec Questions And Relative Clauses; 1971; 1972, Rosenbaum, Harvey
    (F&S 4931)
  - "The Moravian mission at Springplace, Georgia, 1815-1817; 1995", Ruff, Rowena McClinton
  - Metis and Indian-White Contact in the Old Northwest, 1995; Saler, Bethel
    (F&S 4701)
  - "Linguistic Studies Of The Northern Arapaho", 1962; Salzmann, Z.
  - "A basic language analysis of codeswitched sentences, Aug. 1982", Santa Ana-A., Otto
  - Scancarelli, Janine
    - "Grammatical relations and verb agreement in Cherokee", 1988; Scancarelli, Janine
    - [Manuscripts on Cherokee grammar; 1985-1988.], Scancarelli, Janine
  - "Hopi Ethnoanatomy: Summary of work to date", 1969; Schepers, E. M.
    (F&S 4360)
  - "Report on Summer Work on Navaho; 1968", 1969; Schetter, William Z.
  - "Forging Identities: Native Americans And Moravian Missionaries In Pennsylvania And Ohio, 1765-1782", 1995; Schutt, Amy C.
    Disertation
    (F&S 405)
  - "Shawnee sentence profiles in contrastive and non-contrastive syntax", 1964; Schutz, Noel W., Jr.
    Report (2p.) on 1964 grant; report (2p.) on grant to study Shawnee myth, 1971; tape inventory (2p.)
    (F&S 4733)
  - A Historical Perspective on Elsie Clews Parsons' Feminist Theory, 1992; Schwab, Susan Ruth
    (Diss.: Harvard, 1991)
  - Seaman, P. David
    - "Hopi Indian field work; 1976", Seaman, P. David
    - "Hopi dictionary; 1982", Seaman, P. David
  - [Field notes/ translations], 1987; Shaul, David
  - "Preachers, Prophets, and Unruly Men: Religious Upheaval and the Meanings of Masculinity on the Southern Frontier, 1763-1815", 1995; Sheidley, Nathaniel J.
    (F&S 4361)
  - "Report on Field Work: Wishram-Wasco Chinook", 1967-1968; Silverstein, Michael
    Report (2p.) for 1967; report (2p.) for 1968
    (F&S 4893-4894)
  - Fieldwork on Pocomam Central Language, Guatemala, 1972; Simeon, George
    Report (3p.) on 1968-1969 fieldwork; summary of tapes (2p.); outline of monograph (1p.); inventory of tape (1p.)
    (F&S 4684-4687)
  - Research on New England Indian folklore, 1983; Simmons, William S.
  - "Women Say 'Yelo'; Men Say 'Yele': What The Exceptions To the Rules in Lakhota Show", 1994; Sistrunk, Sara A.
  - "A Linguistic Analysis Of Three Versions Of A Yavapai Ickiyuka Text", 1974; Sloane, Emily-Sue
  - "Malecite words...", 1960; Smith, Nicholas N.
    (F&S 288)
  - "Report on a study of the Ioway-Oto language", 1965; Smith, Rondal B.
    (F&S 4179)
  - "Nitzitapi: Portraits and Reflections of a People Called Blackfeet", 1995; Spriggs, Lynne
  - "Report...Oklahoma Seneca-Cayuga...", 1963; Sturtevant, William C.
    (F&S 4728)
  - [Ethnohistoric analysis/ inter-tribal religious exchanges/ Oklahoma], 1994; Swan, Daniel C.
  - "Aleut intonation patterns", 1990-1995; 2 TLsS; Taff, Alice
    Work on morpheme ordering in Aleut conducted in the Pribilof Island, 1993. Accompanying recordings are in Recording Collection 199.
    (Not in F&S)
  - "Ranking in Navajo Nouns; 1972", Taptto, Mary Helen
    (F&S 4578)
  - "Field work done at the Stoney Reserve...", 1972; Taylor, Allan R. (Allan Ross), 1931-
    (F&S 4209)
  - Tedlock, Dennis, Tedlock, Dennis.
    - "Zuni field notes", 1972; Tedlock, Dennis.
      (F&S 4934)
    - "The Story of How a Story Was Made", 1977; Tedlock, Dennis.
      (F&S 4933)
    - "From Prayer to Reprimand: The Inversion of Stress And Pitch In Zuni", 1977; Tedlock, Dennis.
      (F&S 4931a)
    - "In Search Of The Miraculous At Zuni", 1977; Tedlock, Dennis.
      (F&S 4932)
  - "Reduplication in Nisgha. Thesis (M. A.) - Univ. of British Columbia, 1984", 1985; Thompson, Wendy H.
  - "Project report on Mission Indian Federation; 1995", Thorne, Tanis Chapman
  - Research on Yahooskin dialect of Northern Paiute, 1995; Thornes, Tim
    (F&S 4868)
  - "Northern Tlingit Geography", 1991, 1993; Thornton, Thomas F.
    2 reports (1p. each); paper: "Know your place: the organization of Tlingit geographic knowledge" Ethnology 36 (1997)
  - Research on Picuris Pueblo, 1971; Trager, Felicia Harben
    Includes 2 papers: "The cardinal directions at Taos and Picuris" Anthropological Linguistics 13 (1971), 31-37, and "Some aspects of 'time' at Picuris Pueblo (with an addendum on the Nootka," Anthropological Linguistics 13 (1971), 331-338.
  - "Report on the Codex Zouche-Nuttal at the British Museum...", 1971; Troike, Nancy P.
    Images include color photographs of Codex Zouche-Nuttall, Mixtec language picture writing, Oaxaca, Mexico.
    - Codex Zouche Nuttall, 1971
  - Turner, Paul Raymond, Turner, Paul R., 1929-
    - "Report: Highland Chontal Dialect Survey", 1968; Turner, Paul R., 1929-
      (F&S 4543)
    - "Highland Chontal grammar...", 1966; Turner, Paul R., 1929-
      (F&S 4544)
    - "Grammar of the highland Chantal of Oaxaca, Mexico", 1966; Turner, Paul R., 1929-
      (F&S 4542)
  - Vantine, J. Liessmann
    - [Fieldnotes/ Ioway & Otoe languages/ 1982], 1983; Vantine, J. Liessmann
    - [Ioway & Otoe vocabularies], 1983; Vantine, J. Liessmann
  - "Syntactic uses...", 1978; Voegelin, C. F. & F. M.
    (F&S 4362a)
  - Research on the Mesquakie language, Mesquakie Settlement near Tama, Iowa, 1970; Voorhis, Paul H.
    (F&S 4257)
    (F&S 4529)
  - Report on preliminary field work at Pine Ridge, S.D., 1994; TLS, 2p.; Wagoner, Paula L.
  - Archival and Oral History Project in the Yuchi Community, 1994; Wallace, Pamela S.
    Report (1p.); 12 tapes
  - [Field Notes/ Nisgha (Tsimshian language)/ Vancouver, B. C., Canada], 1994; Walsh, Linda G.
  - "West Point Dialect of Northern Sierra Miwok", 1994-1997; Wash, Suzanne M.
    Conditions Governing Access
    Permission of Suzanne Wash is required for access to or reproduction of these materials.
    3 reports (1p. each), 2 outlines of contents (32p., 30p.); field notes, 1996 (31p., 62p., 10p., 53p.) of work with Mildred Burley, David Jeff, Mabel Walloupe, Manuel Jeff; 52 videotapes (Rec. 265); 63 DAT (Rec. 266); 26 videotapes (Rec. 267); 37 videotapes (Rec. 268); 31 DAT, 1996 (Rec. 269); 50 DAT(Rec. 270). Videotapes and sound recordings are restricted.
  - "Hualapai reference grammar", 1981; Bender, Jorgine; Watahomigie, Lucille; Yamamoto, Akira Y.
  - [Report/ Sliammon language], 1992; Watanabe, Honore
  - "Dutchmen and Indians: An Ethnohistory of Intercultural Contacts in New Netherland, 1609-1664", 1994; Waterman, Kees-Jan
  - Fieldwork on Okanagan Indians (Salishan), B.C., 1972; Watkins, Donald
    Report (2p.); inventory of tapes (3p.); "A Boas original," IJAL 40 (1974)
  - "Report of Canadian Eskimo language survey," 1968, 1970; Webster, D. H. and Zibell, W.
    Report (38p.
    (F&S 4256)
  - "Study of Arapaho Tonal Phonology", 1992; Weigel, William F.
    Report (2p.); field notes (123p.); 27 cassette tapes (Rec. 258); contents sheets
  - "Southern California Indian Health Conditions in the Early Reservation Period (1875-1953)", 1996; Weiner, Diane
    Report (1p.); photocopies of manuscript and published materials at other institutions (dealing with Luiseno)
  - "The Christian Indian Movement of Samson Occom As Revitalization in 18th Century Mohegan", 1990; Weinstein-Farson, Laurie
  - "Dine Bikeyah: Environment, Cultural Identity, and Gender in Navajo Country", 1996; Weisiger, Marsha
  - Werner, Oswald
    - "Report on edition of the Young and Morgan dictionary", 1966; Werner, Oswald
      (F&S 4580)
    - "Anatomical atlas of the Navaho, etc. ...", 1967; Werner, Oswald
  - "Report on preliminary fieldwork on the Michif language; Feb. 1983", Weston, Lori Orser
  - "'Give Us A Little Milk': Economics and Ceremony in the Ojibway Fur Trade", 1985; White, Bruce
    (M. A. Thesis)
    (F&S 4582)
  - "Towa (Jemez) Passives and Aspect", 1990; Wilcox. Harold E.
  - "Correlated changes in Ottawa kinship and social organization", Willets, Jane Esther
  - "Oasis on the Northern Plains: A Social History of Fort Clark Fur Trading Post, 1830-1860", 1997; Williams, Randy H.
  - "When New Experiences Come to Be: Narrative Strategies of Walpole Island Hunters and the (Re-)Construction of Cultural Persistence", 1996; Wishart, Robert
  - "A Cherokee Economic Botany From Western North Carolina: Man And Nature In The Southen Appalachians", 1960; Witthoft, John
  - [Iroquois translations], 1995; Wojcik, Jan
  - Wolfart, H. Christophe, Wolfart, H. Christoph
    - "Report on Linguistic Fieldwork among the Plains Cree", 1968; Wolfart, H. Christoph
      (F&S 4191)
    - "Plains Cree Text from the Province of Alberta", 1968; Wolfart, H. Christoph
      (F&S 4192)
  - [Report on Nuuchahnulth recordings], February 15, 2005; 1.0 folder; Woo, Florence
  - Word Order in Nuuchahnulth, 2004; 1.0 item 1 bound recording transcript (111 pages); Woo, Florence
    Separated Materials
    10 sound tape reels ( Mss.Rec.281)
    Transcription and grammatical analysis of Nuuchahnulth language recordings (111 p.)
    Accompanying Nuuchahnulth language recordings can be found in Recording Collection 281.
  - Woodbury, Anthony C.
    - "Report...", 1979; Woodbury, Anthony C.
    - "Field notes & texts on Chevak dialect", 1980; Woodbury, Anthony C.
    - "Study of the Chevak dialect of Central Yup'ik Eskimo", 1981; Woodbury, Anthony C.
  - Wyler, Barbara
    Images include black and white photomechanical prints of the Seneca reservation, New York State, of dwellings, longhouse, dance pavilion, 1964-1965.
    - "The Attitudes of the Seneca Indians towards Land from 1750-1965: An Ethnological Study" / Paper, Wyler, Barbara
      (F&S 4732)
    - "The Senecas and their cultural adaption", 1964; Wyler, Barbara
      Report (4p.) regarding Iroquois masks
      (F&S 618)
  - [Hualapai language materials], 1979; Yamamoto, Akira Y.
  - Young, Gloria A.
    - "An Ethnohistory of Intertribal Dance in Oklahoma", 1981; Young, Gloria A.
    - "Indians in Wild West and Other Traveling Shows, 1986", Young, Gloria A.
  - "Ethnohistory and the Market in Archaeological Artifacts on St. Lawrence Island in Alaska's Bering Straight", 1996; Zimmer, Julie
  - "American Indian Resistance in the West During World War I", 1995; Zissu, Erik M.
  - "Self-Determination for Native Americans: How U. S. is Solving the Problem", 1994; Znamenski, Andrei A.